[Trash collection!]
倒垃圾了
Go knock on the door!
去敲门
Are you friend of Ms. Shi?
你们是石小姐的朋友
Yes.
是
Bring him inside!
快把人送进来
Wei Daiqing speaking.
魏岱擎
[Mr. Wei,]
魏先生
[the person from room 302]
三零二出来的人
[just entered Shengen Book Store.]
现在进了圣恩书店
[Confirmed to be Hua Zhen.]
确认是华桢
Ms. Shi is tied up with official duties,
石小姐有公务来不了
so she asked me to assist.
托我来帮忙
Does Mr. Chen
这位陈先生
have any injuries
除了枪伤之外
other than the gunshot wound?
还有其他的外伤吗
No,
没有
he was shot in the right chest.
他的右胸中了一枪
I've done basic disinfection,
我做了基础的消毒
but the wound is inflamed,
但伤口发炎了
likely still has bullet fragments.
应该是还有弹片残留
Understood, leave it to me.
我知道了 交给我吧
I saw
我看门口
a "Closed" sign at the entrance.
挂着歇业的牌子
We won't have
这里应该不会有
other visitors here, right?
其他人来吧
Normally not.
一般不会
The sign is up year-round
牌子是常年挂着的
to prevent people from accidental entry.
就是为了避免有人进来
This place is a dedicated
这里是救国会
emergency spot for the NSO.
专门用来救急的地方
Alright,
好
then I'll go park the car a bit further
那我去把车停远一点
to avoid attracting police.
免得把警察引过来
Can I help?
有什么我能帮忙的吗
Close the door for me.
帮我把门关上
This is your Council pass.
你们公董局的通行证
Are the two cars behind also with you?
后面那两辆也是
They're my plainclothes officers.
我的便衣
Feng Sir,
科长
there's blood in the back seat.
后座发现血迹
They won't be far.
他们跑不远
Start a search from here,
从这儿开始
radiating outward.
一圈一圈搜
Yes, Sir!
是
Move!
走
Inspector Shi.
石督察
Emergency along the border on Minguo Road.
民国路分界线有情况
The Police Service reported
警务处汇报
that police from Shiliupu Police Station
华界十六铺分局警察
have crossed the border.
刚刚越界了
What are they up to?
他们越界进来干什么
They claim they're pursuing a fugitive.
说是为了找通缉犯
Do we know
知道他们具体
which streets they've headed to?
去了哪条街吗
They went west,
往西边去了
near Changle Road.
长乐路附近
Let's cooperate as needed.
该怎么配合怎么配合吧
This falls under our
这属于和他们的
joint enforcement obligations.
联合执法范畴
Understood.
明白了
How's Chen Hao doing?
陈浩怎么样了
The wound has been stitched up.
伤口已经缝合好了
I happen to have an empty storage room,
我刚好有个库房空着
very secluded
位置很偏僻
and unlikely to draw attention.
不容易被查到
We'll evacuate through the back door
我们从后门撤离
and discuss further once we're there.
到了那面再详细说
Okay.
好
They're here.
他们追来了
Get inside.
先进去
I'll draw them away.
我去把他们引开
You seek a chance to get out.
你们找机会出去
What about you?
那你怎么办
Tan Shiyuan won't let Feng Guangyun
谭施远不会让冯广云
harm me.
对我怎么样的
Take good care of Chen Hao.
你们照顾好陈浩
After you get free,
你脱身之后
meet us at
到望志路五号
No. 5, Wangzhi Road.
跟我们会合
Got it.
好
Who are you looking for?
你找哪位
Mr. Hua,
华二少
glad to meet you again.
咱俩又见面了
Weren't you supposed to be in Nanjing?
你不是去南京了吗
Why are you still here?
怎么还留在这儿呢
Starting a book business now?
在这儿改行卖书啊
Do you need something from me,
找我有事儿吗
Mr. Wei?
魏先生
From you?
找你
I'm too busy
我忙得很
for that.
没时间单独找你
We've received intelligence
我们得到情报
that there are Communists
这个书店里
frequenting this bookstore.
有共产党出没
And here you are again,
倒是你啊
Mr. Hua,
华二少
care to explain?
你解释解释吧
Always popping up
你怎么又出现在
where Communists are rumored to be.
有共产党出现的地方呢
I don't need to report my actions to you.
我没有必要向你汇报
Do you have a search warrant?
搜查令呢
This trivial matter
这点儿小事儿
doesn't require a warrant.
不需要搜查令
As long as I'm here,
现在我在这儿
you need
你要搜查
a warrant to search.
就必须出示搜查令
You know
你知道
I left the Shanghai Garrison Command,
我从淞沪警备司令部
right?
出去了吧
Then under what authority
那你是以什么身份
are you searching my place?
搜查我的地方
A legitimate authority.
合理合法的身份
I can't
具体什么身份
disclose specifics.
不能告诉你
Serving the nation, duty calls,
为党国效忠 责无旁贷
it doesn't matter what my title is.
什么身份不重要
Found a
这么快就找到
new gig so quickly, huh?
新的落脚地了
Secret Service
复兴社
of the Reviving Society?
特务处啊
Any role will bring you to justice.
什么身份都能办你
You've seen what you needed to see.
该看的也都看了
Shall I personally escort you out?
要我亲自送你出去吗
No rush.
不着急
Mr. Hua,
华二少
I've heard
我听我的人讲
you visited
你去了一趟
an apartment at No. 16, Maiqi Road,
麦琪路十六号的公寓
room 302, to be precise.
那栋公寓的三零二房间
That's a known safehouse
可是救国会的
for the NSO,
一处安全房
which is
救国会
affiliated with the Communists.
可跟共产党有染呢
Mr. Hua,
华二少
tell me,
说说吧
why were you there?
干吗要去那儿啊
Can't I visit someone?
做客也不行吗
A visit?
做客
Is the occupant a friend of yours?
那儿住的是你的朋友啊
Just an acquaintance.
认识而已
How did you meet?
怎么认识的
Where did you meet?
在哪儿认识的
Since you're so eager to chat,
既然这么想聊天
why don't we go somewhere else?
不如换个地方聊
How about the Reviving Society?
复兴社怎么样
Brazen as always.
还是那么地有恃无恐
I'm telling you,
我可告诉你
if you end up
你要是去了
at the Secret Service of the Reviving Society,
复兴社特务处
no one will be able to help you.
可就没有人再捞你了
Isn't that
这不就是你
the purpose of your visit?
此行的目的吗
Wait!
等等
You're not acting brazenly,
你这不是有恃无恐
you seem nervous,
你这是紧张啊
not like your usual self.
不像从前的你
This is your
这是你最后
last chance to take me
带走我的机会了
before I
你要是再不走
walk out of here.
我可就自己走
Hua Zhen!
华桢
Another step
再动一下
and I'll shoot you!
我绝对崩了你
Stop testing my patience!
别再考验我的耐心
You were so eager trying to lure me out.
就这么想引我出去
What's the plan?
为什么
Expecting your
是外面埋伏着
Communist friends outside,
你的共产党同党
or are they
还是里面藏着
Put the gun down!
把枪放下
No more games!
别耍花样
Stay calm.
别冲动
Remember what
别忘了愚先生
Mr. Yu tasked us with.
交给我们的任务是什么
Shut up!
闭嘴
Mr. Yu said,
愚先生说了
he wants him alive.
抓活的
Zhou,
周哥
we've looked everywhere.
咱们都找了一圈了
Where is he?
人呢
It's Hua Zhen!
是华桢
After him!
上
There is indeed
外面果然有
Communist ambushing outside.
埋伏的共产党
We can't let him get away like this.
绝不能让他这么跑了
Cover me!
掩护我
Stop right there!
给我站住
Hua Zhen,
华桢
turn around slowly.
慢慢转过来
Drop your gun on the ground!
把枪扔到地上
Where's Hua Zhen?
华桢呢
He got into a car and headed east.
上了一辆车往东边跑了
We need to catch up!
我们必须追上他
The police are almost here.
警察快到了
Let's head back to the Reviving Society.
先回复兴社
Stay undercover!
注意隐蔽
You will get shot!
你不怕挨枪子儿吗
Are you hurt?
你没受伤吧
No.
没有
How come you came over?
你怎么也赶过来了
I got a report
我在公董局
at the Council about
接到警务处报告
someone targeting Changle Road,
有人盯上了长乐路
so I rushed over.
我就赶过来了
Thanks.
谢谢
How's Chen Hao doing now?
陈浩现在情况怎么样了
Any better?
好些了吗
He's managing,
还好
thanks to Mrs. Ji,
季太太
who took care of his wounds.
已经帮陈浩处理了伤口
How did he get shot?
他怎么中的枪
To save me.
为了救我
Feng Guangyun from the Shiliupu Police Station
十六铺分局的冯广云
had abducted two officers from the Fourth Station,
绑架两名四所警员
one of whom has been killed.
一名已经遇害了
The other,
另一位
Luo Minmin,
骆珉敏
was rescued by me and Chen Hao.
被我和陈浩救了出来
He got shot
他就是在救人的时候
during the rescue.
中的枪
This way.
这边
Mrs. Ji.
季太太
Come in quickly.
快进来
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
are you all okay?
你们都没事吧
Ms. Shi saved me.
石小姐赶过来救了我
How's Chen Hao?
陈浩呢
He's inside.
在屋里
He hasn't woken up yet
他还没醒
and still unconscious.
正在休息
Noted.
好
He's inside.
他在里边
His gunshot wound, how is it?
他的枪伤怎么样了
The bullet
这一枪
penetrated from his back to his chest
是从后背到前胸贯穿
but fortunately didn't hit
幸好没有伤到
any major organs or blood vessels.
重要的器官和血管
Now,
目前
the main issue is the wound infection.
就是伤口发炎的问题
I've done a debridement
我已经给弹道
and cleaned the wound.
做了扩创消毒
Were all the bullet fragments removed?
弹片残留都取出来了吗
They've all been removed,
已经全部取出来了
successfully.
很顺利
Mr. Chen has a strong constitution
陈先生的体质很好
as well as
而且
a strong willpower.
意志力也很顽强
Rest assured,
你们放心
he will recover gradually.
他会慢慢好起来的
Good.
好
Let's step outside for now.
那我们先出去吧
Let him rest.
让他好好休息一下
With Chen Hao's
以陈浩现在
current condition,
这样子的身体状况
staying here isn't a long-term solution,
待在这里不是长久之计
especially when all major hospitals
想必各大医院
probably have received the arrest warrant.
都已经收到了通缉令
After a few days' rest,
休整几日
we'll need to move him
我们还是得把他转移到
to a safer place
更安全
with better medical facilities.
治疗条件更好的地方
Ideally,
按理说
I wouldn't want
其实不应该
to trouble you further,
再麻烦二位了
but I'm stretched thin as it is,
但是我实在是分身乏术
so I must ask for your help.
所以只好拜托
Understood.
明白
I have connections with the NSO.
我跟救国会一直有往来
I can ask them for assistance.
我可以让他们想想办法
I heard about your efforts
其实我之前就听说过
to rescue Mr. Peng,
你们营救彭记者的事情
but
但是后来
what exactly happened
到底发生了什么
that led to Mr. Chen getting shot?
陈先生为什么会中枪呢
Recent events are linked
最近发生的这些事情
to a military supplies smuggling case
都和彭记者发现的
Mr. Peng uncovered.
军需品走私案有关系
[After rescuing Mr. Peng,]
我们救出彭记者之后
[we decided to follow]
决定顺着他的线索
[his leads further.]
继续往下查
[I went to Wusong Port]
我去了趟吴淞口
[and found out that on the 6th of this month,]
发现这个月的六号
[more cargo]
还有一批货
[would be shipped]
会从吴淞口
[to Shiliupu Wharf]
运到十六铺码头
[and then transported to Japan]
然后通过新荣丸号货船
[on the Shinei Maru ship.]
运往日本
[We also found]
我们还发现了
[two critical pieces of evidence:]
两样关键性的证据
[a pass]
一是通行证
[with seals]
上面盖有
[from the Shanghai Customs District]
江海关
[Anti-smuggling Section]
总税务司署缉私科
[and the Public Security Bureau,]
和上海市公安局的公章
[and a cargo manifest]
二是货单
[listing the]
上面有这批货的
[seller's details,]
卖方信息
which will be
这两样东西
handed to Feng Guangyun
会在货到码头之后
once the goods arrive at the dock.
交到冯广云手上
Feng of the Criminal Investigation Dept.
十六铺分局
at Shiliupu Police Station?
刑警科的科长
Yes.
对
Did you see
那你看到了
who was the seller on the manifest?
货单上的卖家是谁吗
It could be a company,
可能是某个公司
or it might be my brother.
也有可能是我的哥哥
You two
你们俩先在外面
take a break outside.
休息一下
I need to
我正好
change Mr. Chen's dressing.
要给陈先生换个药
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
could you come in and help me?
你可以进去帮我吗
You stay here.
你先休息
I'll go check
我出去看看
if anyone is following us.
有没有人追过来
Mrs. Ji,
季太太
is there something
你是有什么事情
you need to tell me alone?
要单独和我说吗
Not all the
子弹的碎片
bullet fragments were removed.
没有完全取出来
There are still remnants in his lung.
肺部还有残留
If I arrange for him
那如果我现在马上
to go to a hospital now,
安排他去医院
can they be removed?
取得出来吗
It's hard.
很难
Even with first-rate surgical conditions
即便是手术条件一流
and
而且
ample blood transfusions,
还能提供大量的输血
the risks are high.
风险也很大
Moreover,
更何况
he can't go to a hospital right now.
他现在根本不能去医院
This gunshot wound
这次枪伤
will definitely
肯定会给他带来
cause irreversible damage.
不可逆转的伤害
What kind of damage?
什么样的伤害
The through-and-through wound
子弹留下的贯穿伤
will manage to heal.
会勉强愈合
Formation of continuous
但是会生成
scar tissue is inevitable.
贯通的瘢痕组织
Many complications
很多后遗症
will accompany him
都会伴随
for the rest of his life.
他整个的下半生
Chen Hao.
陈浩
are you awake?
你醒了吗
Ms. Shi.
石老师
[Hold on,]
你等我一下
[I'll get you...]
我马上就给你
Wait.
等等
Sorry,
对不起
my undercover mission at the station...
我在分局的潜伏任务
This is Mrs. Ji,
这位是季太太
a friend of mine.
我的朋友
She performed the surgery on you.
是她给你做的手术
She's also one of us.
她也是我们其中的一员
Thank you, Mrs. Ji.
谢谢你 季太太
Sorry,
对不起
my undercover mission at the station
我在分局的潜伏任务
failed.
失败了
But I didn't expose the organization
但我没有暴露组织
or my identity.
也没有暴露自己的身份
You should be safe.
你们应该都是安全的
Don't think too much.
你别想太多了
Staying alive
先活着
gives us a chance to win.
才有胜利的机会
Um.
好
Exactly,
对
staying alive is winning.
活着就是胜利
You need to recover quickly.
你要尽快好起来
I'm still waiting for you
我还等着你
to come back to my French class.
来上法语班呢
Alright.
好
And,
还有件事
Xiang Yuansheng has volunteered.
向远生主动申请
He said seriously
他希望加入
that he wanna
邓先生的队伍
join Mr. Deng's team.
说的时候很认真
OK.
好
I see.
我知道了
I'll report it to the higher-ups.
我马上会向上级汇报
[I'll tell the organization]
我会告诉组织
[that Xiang Yuansheng]
零三七同志
[has passed No. 037's assessment.]
通过了对向远生的考察
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I won't let him
我不会
risk it on his own.
让他一个人冒险的
Don't tell them
不要告诉他们
I still have shrapnel
我身体里面
in my body.
还有没有取出的弹片
OK.
知道了
Mr. Chen is awake.
陈先生醒了
Captain.
队长
Miss Luo,
骆警官
you have to change
你得好好改改
your crying habit.
你这个爱哭的毛病啊
Have you slept enough?
这次睡够了吧
Finally.
总算睡够了
I told you I can make it.
我就说我能挺过来吧
Mrs. Ji said the surgery was a success.
季太太说手术很成功
Soon, I will be able to run.
没两三天都能下床跑了
Don't think about that.
都这样了 还想着跑呢
Have a good rest.
赶紧歇着吧
The clues you found in Wusong Port...
你在吴淞口查到的线索
No worries.
放心吧
I'll keep digging
我会一直查下去
[until I find all the evidence.]
直到找到所有的证据
It's the only thing
这是我现在
I want to do.
唯一想做的事儿
The wanted notice
现在整个上海
can be seen throughout Shanghai.
都能看到陈浩的通缉令
He's safer
他待在这里
here.
还算安全
I'll bring you something
我尽快给你们
to eat and use soon.
送些吃的和用的过来
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
there's something
有件事儿
I should have told you
我本应该在上次
before I left Shanghai
离开上海之前
last time.
就告诉你
What is it?
什么事
About Zhang Runjin.
是关于张润金的
2 months ago,
两个多月前
he died.
他牺牲了
When I was
我被魏岱擎
locked up
关在
in the Shanghai Garrison Command,
淞沪警备司令部的时候
Wei Daiqing told me
魏岱擎告诉我的
that Mr. Zhang was killed due to
他说张先生是共产党
his identity as a
他遇害后
communist,
人就被埋在
and he's buried in the wasteland
淞沪警备司令部
outside the Command.
外面的荒地
Mr. Xiang.
向先生
Li Qiushi and I
我和黎秋实
were both
都受到过
protected and helped by him.
他的保护和帮助
I'm sorry
他遇害了
about his death.
我很难过
Although
虽然已经
it's been some time,
过去了一段时间
I think
但我觉得
I still need to tell you personally.
还是有必要亲口告诉你
Actually,
其实
after his disappearance,
老张失踪过后
I was mentally prepared.
我有心理准备的
Thank you for
不过还是谢谢你
telling me about it.
告诉我这个结果
I've submitted to the organization
我已经向组织提交了
a plan to expose the smuggling case.
曝光走私案的行动计划
We should expect a response soon.
应该很快就有回复
Feng Guangyun's manifest
冯广云手上的货单
and pass
和通行证
are crucial evidence.
是至关重要的证据
As long as they're available,
只要能拿到这两张证据
we can confirm their crime.
就能坐实他们的罪行
It's not easy to get them.
想要拿到证据并不容易
Luckily,
好在
Feng Guangyun
冯广云不是一个
is an impatient man.
沉得住气的人
The plan has two steps.
所以计划分为两步
First, expose smuggling and treason
先通过报纸新闻的方式
through newspapers.
曝光走私集团卖国行为
Then, get the public opinion against him.
再把舆论对准他
He must show his flaws.
冯广云一定会露出破绽
But Mr. Peng
但是彭记者
is on
已经上了
Tan Shiyuan's blacklist.
谭施远的黑名单
It's hard for him
想要发声
to report it.
那太困难了
A playwright in the Left Alliance
左联里有一位
surnamed Xia
姓夏的剧作家
is close to us.
和我们关系非常密切
There's a fan meeting
他在国泰大剧院
at the Guotai Theatre.
有一个影迷见面会
Many reporters
到时候会有大量的记者
will attend.
来现场
Mr. Xia said
夏先生说过
he would do his best
只要以救亡运动有利
if it's good for salvation.
必以血诚拥护
[I think]
所以我在想
we can take
我们可以把握好
the advantage of the fan meeting.
这个影迷见面会的机会
I'll contact Mr. Peng.
那我跟彭记者联络
No.
不用了
I'll contact him.
我去联络彭记者
Your mission
季太太
in Shanghai
组织要求
has been terminated
从今天开始
by the organization.
你在上海的任务终止了
Wei Daiqing targeted the tailor shop.
魏岱擎盯上裁缝铺
Whatever the reason,
不管什么原因
you can't stay here.
你不能留在上海
Here are some clothes,
这里面有一些衣服
and the ticket to Hong Kong
这是今晚去香港的船票
by a French cargo ship.
法国的货船
The most suitable one
这是我从公董局
I can get from the Council.
弄到最快的船票
Here's your ID.
这是你的证件
Tao Lanxin.
陶兰心
I haven't
我已经很多年
seen my name
没有看见过
in years.
自己的名字了
I didn't expect this evacuation
没想到这次撤离
to be so sudden.
竟然这么突然
It's discipline.
这是组织的纪律
You must evacuate immediately.
你必须马上撤离
There're only
现在小组只剩下
3 people left in our group.
你 我 陈浩三个人
Chen Hao is injured.
陈浩现在受伤了
I can't put you at risk.
我不能再让你去冒险了
You can't say that.
这个不能称之为冒险
It's our mission.
这是你我的使命
Zhang Runjin's death
张润金同志
will not be in vain.
不会白白牺牲的
I believe
我相信
the revolution will soon see its light.
革命很快就会迎来曙光
[Take care of ourselves.]
我们都要保护好自己
I don't know
只是不知道
when I'll see you again.
下一次见面是什么时候
But we'll meet again.
会有那一天的
I will be back.
我总会回来的
Take care.
保重
Xinyu,
馨毓
you too.
你也是
When did she disappear?
什么时候不见的
It's almost
快三点钟
at 3 p.m...
三点钟的时候来
How did she slip away?
不是让你盯着她吗
Actually,
不是 是
I've been
我 我是盯着她
staring at her.
我跟了段时间
But I lost finally.
跟 跟丢了呀
Has she
她去过
been to the phone booth?
门口的公用电话亭吗
No.
没有
There's no phone inside,
裁缝铺里没有电话
who told her to go to the Store?
谁通知她去的圣恩书店
Did anyone come
她不见之前
before she disappeared?
有人来过吗
Many have come,
进进出出人很多
including
公董局那个
Inspector Shi
姓石的女督察员
from the Council.
她也来过
She was here to tip her off.
她是来通风报信的
We arrived at the Store at 4 p.m.
我们四点钟到的书店
but she left here at 3 p.m.
她三点钟在这儿不见的
The timing was just right.
时间刚好对得上
Send people
马上派人
to guard all the docks,
盯住所有的码头
bus and railway stations.
车站 火车站
Arrest her if she shows up.
一旦发现 立刻逮捕
[Xiang Yuansheng,]
向远生
[I heard you]
今天你和魏岱擎
[confront Wei Daiqing]
对峙的时候
[from inside.]
我在里面全部都听见了
[Weren't]
你当时
[you afraid that he'd kill you?]
真的不害怕他杀了你吗
That was my only choice.
那是我当时唯一的选择
How brave!
你真勇敢
Mrs. Ji and I
我和季太太待在里面
were stressed,
都紧张坏了
and afraid
生怕你在外面
something would happen.
出什么意外
You're brave too.
你也很勇敢
If both of you
要不是你和季太太
haven't moved Chen Hao here,
把陈浩顺利地转移过来
it would be
我在外面
useless for me
争取再多的时间
to buy more time.
也只是徒劳
You rest here
今天晚上
tonight.
你就在这儿休息吧
I'll check on Chen Hao.
我一会儿看看陈浩
I can take care of him
我可以和你一起去
with you.
照顾队长
No need. Take a rest.
不用了 你赶紧休息吧
You didn't
这一天
[have a good rest today.]
你也没怎么好好睡觉
I'll take
晚上呢
care of him tonight.
就我来值班
Tomorrow morning...
等到明天白天
What are you doing?
你干吗呀
What else can I do?
还能干什么呀
Sleep.
睡觉
Aren't there any other rooms available?
这儿没别的空房间了吗
No.
没了
Drink some water.
喝点水
No,
没事儿
I can drink it myself.
你放那儿我自己来吧
Pay attention to the wound.
你就不怕伤口再扯开
It's awkward.
这也太别扭了
You have no choice.
没办法
Get used to it.
慢慢习惯吧
How's your watch?
手表好用吗
It sometimes runs fast
有时候走得快
and sometimes slow.
有时候走得慢
Anyway,
反正
it's never accurate.
从来没有准过
Give it back.
还给我
I saved up
这可是我
half a year to buy it.
攒了半年薪水买的
It's given to me,
哪有送出去
you can't take it back.
还要回来的呀
I'll buy you a new one
等我回南京啊
when I get back to Nanjing.
有钱了给你买块新的
OK.
好
That's a deal.
一言为定
We said
不是说好
we were a team.
我们是一个队伍的吗
As teammates,
一个队伍
you couldn't isolate me.
怎么能孤立我呢
I didn't.
谁孤立你了
I'm taking care of Chen Hao.
我这不是照顾陈浩呢吗
As teammates,
一个队伍
we should act together.
就应该一起行动
Anyway,
不管怎么样
I'll also
反正我今天晚上
sleep here tonight.
也要睡在这儿
Thank you for making my bed.
谢谢你给我铺床
If you sleep here,
你睡这儿
where will Xiang Yuansheng sleep?
向远生睡哪儿啊
Captain, you're awake.
队长 你醒了
Do you
队长
feel better?
你现在觉得好点了吗
Yes.
好多了
Captain,
队长 我跟你说
today,
今天
Mrs. Ji and Ms. Shi
季太太和石小姐
were amazing.
特别厉害
What did they do?
她们怎么了
We're in a critical situation
今天在圣恩书店的时候
at the Store.
情况特别地危急
However,
但是
even so,
就是在最慌张的时候
they made
她们也做出了
the right decision
最正确的决定
[to save]
救人 转移
[and transfer people.]
一步都不含糊
[They've always]
而且从头到尾
[been resolute,]
我都没有看到
[without any panic.]
她们一丝慌张
[Captain,]
队长
[I learned]
我才知道
that women can also
原来女孩子
be so bold
也可以这样有魄力
and responsible.
有担当
Do you want
你也想成为
to be like them?
像她们那样的人吗
When I joined the Fourth Sation,
我来四所的时候
I just wanna be a police officer.
其实只想要当一名警察
But
不过
I've been
这段时间
doing a lot of thinking.
我回想了很多
Honestly, I like
我觉得也不只是这样
to do
我喜欢的
anything meaningful
是和你们在一起
with you.
做有意义的事情
Minmin,
珉敏
maybe you're getting to
有可能是你
know yourself.
越来越了解自己了
I think so, too.
我觉得也是
[Do you want to be like]
你真的想要成为像
Ms. Shi
石小姐
and Mrs. Ji?
季太太那样的人吗
Of course.
当然
Captain,
队长
if I
你觉得
work hard
如果我从现在
from now on,
开始努力的话
will I have a chance
我有机会
to be like them?
成为像她们那样的人吗
Definitely.
只要你想
As you wish.
一定有可能的
I'll work hard.
我会努力的
Good.
好
[Come out.]
出来
[What do you want?]
干吗呀
[Don't move.]
别动
Why?
你们想干吗
Show your ID.
证件
I want one.
给我烤红薯
How about this?
就拿这个
Zijin Tailor Shop.
子衿裁缝铺
Mrs. Ji.
季太太
[Junyu,]
珺昱
[wait.]
你等一下
[I have something to show you.]
我有个东西给你看
[This is the wedding dress]
这是我给你做的
[I made for you.]
结婚礼服
[It's not finished.]
但还没完工呢
[Do you like it?]
你喜欢吗
[For me?]
给我
[I'm not busy lately.]
最近铺子里不忙
[I found some time to make it.]
我就抽时间每天做一点
[Almost taken shape.]
已经雏形出来了
[I remember]
我记得
[the first time I saw you,]
我第一次看见你的时候
[you were 19,]
你才十九岁
[and]
那一年
[had just graduated]
你从莫斯科
[from radio in Moscow.]
刚学完无线电专业回来
[You didn't bring any drawings]
你身上没有带一张图纸
[or parts.]
和一个零件
[You said everything]
你说所有的东西
[was in your head.]
都放在你的脑子里
[You barely say anything]
除了发件和收件之外
[except for those related to telegrams.]
你几乎一句话都不说
[I am the same now.]
我现在也不爱说话
[But I enjoy talking to you.]
只是爱和你说话
[Here's something]
这里面有一些
[to eat and use.]
吃的和用的
[That will last you]
应该你们可以用
[three or four days.]
三四天了
[Remember to burn]
到时候衣服换了下来
[the dirty clothes]
你们一定要烧了
[to avoid trouble.]
免得被人看见有麻烦
[I've got a car for you]
给你们准备了一辆车
for precaution.
以防万一
Here's the medicine.
这是给你带的药
How do you feel?
你伤口怎么样了
Much better.
好多了
I feel like
我感觉我可以
I can walk.
下床自由活动了
Please take care of him.
麻烦你们一定要看着他
Don't let him go around.
让他千万不要乱跑
[Don't worry.]
放心吧
We knew it.
我们知道的
[Besides,]
对了
some news about the smuggling case.
走私案那边有新情况
We're making progress.
事情有转机了
Mr. Peng
今天彭记者
went to the Guotai Theatre.
去了国泰大剧院
At a fan meeting,
在一个影迷见面会上
he spoke to reporters
当着很多同行记者的面
about what happened
把他的遭遇
to him
和调查出来的情况
and the investigation.
全都披露出来了
I believe
我相信很快
that Feng Guangyun and Tan Shiyuan
冯广云和谭施远
will be pushed to the forefront.
就会被推到风口浪尖
Their crimes
到时候他们的罪行
will be exposed finally.
会彻底被曝光
What we need most now
现在我们最需要的
is concrete evidence.
就是铁证
[Feng Guanyun]
冯广云不是一个
[is an impatient man.]
能沉得住气的人
As long as he panics,
只要他乱了阵脚
we have a chance.
我们就有机会行动
And,
另外
Mrs. Ji
季太太今天
was arrested by Wei Daiqing.
被魏岱擎逮捕了
Take care of yourselves.
你们要多多小心